Guide to the George Cooper Pardee Scrapbooks, 1889-1912
Department of Special Collections
George Cooper Pardee Scrapbooks,
1889-1912
Special Collections M0162
Pardee, George Cooper
19 v.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
unknown
Biography
George Cooper Pardee, born 25 July 1857 in San Francisco, California, was a doctor who specialized in diseases of the eye and ear. He served as mayor of Oakland (1893-1895) and as governor of California (1903-1907).
Scope and Content
Summary: Volumes of newspaper clippings (1889-1912) covering Pardee's career and the general political picture of the time.
Container List
- Aug. 10, 1889-March 5, 1890Dealing primarily with efforts to combat monopolistic water interests (Volume 1)
- March 6, 1890-June 4, 1890Continues water fight (Volume 2)
- March 10, 1891-Oct. 28, 1891Various political issues, including fiscal, railroad, poolrooms (Volume 3)
- Oct. 22, 1889-April 4, 1892(End section out of order) (Volume 4)
- April 2, 1892-Sept. 8, 1892 (Volume 5)
- Sept. 1892-Feb. 1893 (Volume 6)
- Feb. 22, 1893-June 21, 1893 (Volume 7)
- June 22-Nov.14 1893 (Volume 8)
- Nov.14, 1893-Aug.21, 1894 (Volume 9)
- Aug. 22, 1894-July 3, 1896 (Volume 10)
- July 6, 1896- Feb. 22, 1898 (Volume 11)
- Feb. 23, 1898- July 31, 1899 (Volume 12)
- Aug. 7-Dec. 28, 1899 (Volume 13)
- April 6, 1900- July 7, 1901 (Volume 14)
- Jan 2, 1900-Feb. 8, 1901 (Volume 15)
- Feb. 7, 1901- Sept. 26, 1901 (Volume 16)
- Jan 10, 1903-March 2, 1905 (Volume 17)
- March 4, 1905- Nov. 29, 1910 (Volume 18)
- Dec. 1905-April, 1912(Disorgainized; also contains postcards from different worldwide places) (Volume 19)
- Index (Volume 20)